

(+66)86-715-6636

ladamas.sa@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/lsaiphet

11/327 Ceil by Sansiri, Ekkamai 12 Alley, Klong Tan Nuea, Wattana, Bangkok 10110

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

- MS Office
- Excel (Lookup, Pivot Table, Power Query, etc.)
- MS Power BI
- Business Tools (Business Model Canvas, Value Proposition, OKR, e-commerce metrics)
- Data Analysis
- Logical Thinking
- Certified instructor

LANGUAGES

English: Proficient (CEFR level C2)

Thai: Native

LADAMAS SAIPHET

Motivated analyst with strong mathematical background and very logical thinking. Detail-oriented, confident with big data, with proven records of revenue achievements. 6 years of experience in various business sectors such as airlines, logistics and FMCG. Familiar with multicultural companies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Account Manager APAC | Farm Frites (Thailand) Ltd.

November 2021 - Present

- Analyze data and provide reports direct to C-level executive to support business plan.
- Monitor sales performance on both volume and value aspects, e.g., pricing, contract performance and renewal plan, overdue invoices, demand planning, stock level, and supply capacity.
- Collaborate with APAC Regional Sales Managers (across 6 countries) to assure of right actions at the right time.
- Monitor market data and import/export statistics to drive our brand positioning.
- Gatekeeper on budgeting for allocation and opportunities.

Division Manager, Revenue & Cost Management | Kerry Express (Thailand) Pub Co. Ltd.

July 2020 - October 2021

- Analyzed big data (internal and external) to understand market insights, trends, and gaps to be improved.
- Proposed strategies and plans to drive sales and optimize revenue through marketing campaigns/promotions with estimated cost and forecasted return on each plan.
- Managed projects and coordinated with multi-functional teams to ensure of project launch.
- Monitored and analyzed campaign results. Implemented tracking dashboards and provided summary reports on performance, ROI, etc.
- Defined customer segmentation. Identified their needs to create strategy for customer loyalty.

<u>Achievements</u>

- Restructured customer segmentation and reprioritized key areas for more efficient plans and budget spending.
- Launched 5 main promotions nationwide (during the pandemic of Covid-19 and price war). This increases sales volume up to +51%.
- Launched a new pricing structure in 2021 to meet market's expectation. This increases +13% of sales volume in January 2021 comparing to December 2020.

Executive Assistant to CEO, Project Analyst | NokScoot Airlines Co. Ltd.

January 2018 - June 2020

Developed and implemented projects based on CEO's vision to improve company productivity such as:

- Revenue and cost analyses: on each product, route, channel, and customer.
- Defined customer segmentation and set the right target group for marketing strategy.
- Proposed plans to improve customers' experience and increase sales through customer touchpoints (online and offline journey).
- Studied and monitored competitors in various aspects: marketing campaigns, revenue, business plans, etc.

Lecturer | College of ICT, Rangsit University

August 2017 - December 2017

Lectured Mathematics and Basic Investment for Thai and International students.

EDUCATION

Chulalongkorn University, August 2017

M.Sc. Mathematics | GPA 3.33 Research areas: Graph Theory, Combinatorics, Design Theory

Khon Kaen University, March 2014

B.Sc. Mathematics | GPA 3.40 (second class honor)